Okay, let's try it again.
좋아요, 다시 시도해 보겠습니다.
We saved this one, but let's do one more.
우리는 이것을 저장했지만, 하나 더 해보자.
Just one more.
하나만 더.
We keep it. One more.
우리는 그것을 유지합니다. 하나 더.
We keep this one too.
우리는 이것도 보관합니다.
Gyu Hui.
규희.
Gyu Hui!
규희!
I can't do this.
나는 이것을 할 수 없습니다.
Because?
왜냐하면?
Hey...
안녕...
Just today they intern Nara,
바로 오늘 그들은 나라를 인턴으로 삼고,
and you had to make the song so difficult.
그리고 당신은 노래를 너무 어렵게 만들어야 했어요.
Not that anyone who knows how to play this appears out of nowhere.
이거 할 줄 아는 사람은 아니지 갑자기 나타납니다.
Maybe... Hee Jeong?
어쩌면... 희정?
Hee Jeong?
정희?
Do you think I didn't try to call her?
내가 그 사람에게 전화를 안 했을 것 같나요?
saw the sheet music
악보를 봤어
and said it would take at least a week.
그리고 적어도 일주일은 걸릴 거라고 하더군요.
I don't blame you,
나는 당신을 비난하지 않습니다
I'm just saying take it easy.
그냥 편하게 지내라는 뜻이에요.
Be a little more flexible.
조금 더 유연해지세요.
That?
저것?
Yun Ju?
윤주?
I guess someone did come.
누군가 왔었나 봅니다.
I heard you were back in Korea.
한국에 돌아왔다고 들었습니다.
I didn't expect this!
나는 이것을 기대하지 않았다!
Hello, Do Hyun.
안녕하세요, 도현님.
Jun Kyung, did you eat?
준경아 밥 먹었어?
I was waiting to eat with you.
나는 당신과 함께 식사하기를 기다리고있었습니다.
Do you have a long way to go to finish?
완결까지 갈길이 멀다?
It might take a little longer.
조금 더 시간이 걸릴 수 있습니다.
I think I'll have lunch with Jung Hoon later.
나중에 정훈이랑 점심 같이 먹을 것 같아.
Make sure you eat,
식사를 꼭 하세요.
you must be hungry.
배가 고프겠군요.
Jin Ho,
진호,
Have you seen Bom?
봄님 보신 적 있나요?
I can't find it anywhere.
어디에서도 찾을 수 없습니다.
Ja Yeong,
자영,
are you okay?
괜찮아?
I must have fallen asleep for a second.
아마 잠시 잠들었나 봐요.
I dreamed about Bom.
나는 봄에 대한 꿈을 꾸었습니다.
It felt so real that I thought it was happening.
너무 현실감이 있어서 그런 일이 일어나고 있다고 생각했어요.
God.
하나님.
So it was just a dream.
그러니 그것은 단지 꿈일 뿐이었습니다.
It must have scared you.
겁이 났나 봐요.
Yes.
예.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
You only have to have five million ready.
500만개만 준비하면 됩니다.
Many teachers are looking those optional subjects,
많은 선생님들이 찾고 계십니다. 선택과목은,
and the complaints are endless.
불만사항은 끝이 없습니다.
As long as you have that amount ready, You'll be fine.
해당 금액이 준비되어 있는 한, 괜찮을 거예요.
Okay,
알았어
finish and come quickly.
끝내고 빨리 오세요.
The director liked it.
감독님이 좋아하셨어요.
Send your account details to Jung Hoon.
계정 정보를 정훈에게 보내세요.
Isn't that too formal?
너무 형식적인거 아냐?
Thank you.
감사합니다.
- Enjoy your food. - Thank you.
- 음식을 즐겨보세요. - 감사합니다.
I haven't eaten hagfish in years.
나는 몇 년 동안 먹장어를 먹지 않았습니다.
Just when I played, it brought back memories.
놀다가 추억이 되살아나더군요.
In first year, on Jongno Street,
첫 해에는 종로 거리에서
I played the song you had made on the piano.
당신이 만든 노래를 피아노로 연주했어요.
Do you remember when people gathered?
사람들이 언제 모였는지 기억하시나요?
Do you know how much I liked you back then?
그땐 내가 널 얼마나 좋아했는지 알아?
Do even those memories bother you?
그 기억마저도 괴롭나요?
I also thought about the past.
나도 과거를 생각했다.
At that time...
그 당시...
I also liked you a lot.
나도 당신을 많이 좋아했어요.
But...
하지만...
like you said,
당신이 말했듯이,
They are just memories.
그것은 단지 추억일 뿐입니다.
I'm sorry, I should go.
미안해요. 가봐야 할 것 같아요.
Jun Kyung is waiting. I shouldn't stay here.
준경이 기다리고 있어요. 나는 여기에 머물면 안 된다.
And what about me?
그리고 나는 어떻습니까?
You are what I need now.
당신은 지금 나에게 필요한 것입니다.
We finished a long time ago.
우리는 오래 전에 끝냈습니다.
I will do the best I can as Daniel's father...
다니엘의 아버지로서 최선을 다하겠습니다..
But that's all there is between us.
하지만 그게 우리 사이의 전부입니다.
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
Hey!
여기요!
I know.
알아요.
I know Jun Kyung is with Do Hyun now.
지금은 준경이 도현이랑 있는 거 알아요.
But they've only been together two years.
하지만 둘은 함께한 지 2년 밖에 되지 않았습니다.
We have known each other for a long time...
우리는 오랫동안 서로를 알고 있었습니다...
and we have...
그리고 우리는 ...
to Daniel.
다니엘에게.
I thought that made me stronger.
그게 나를 더 강하게 만들었다고 생각했어요.
There is no stronger or weaker.
더 강한 것도 약한 것도 없습니다.
So,
그래서,
what are you going to do now?
이제 무엇을 할 건가요?
Don't know.
모르겠어요.
What do I do now?
이제 어떻게 해야 하나요?
Joy and sadness
기쁨과 슬픔
they always seem to come out of nowhere.
항상 갑자기 나타나는 것 같습니다.
Especially sadness.
특히 슬픔.
There is a tribe in Africa
아프리카에 부족이 있습니다
who believes that the rain It is a sign of God's pain.
비를 믿는 사람 이는 하나님의 고통의 표시입니다.
So when it rains,
그래서 비가 오면
they stay outside the town
그들은 마을 밖에 있어요
until it stops raining...
비가 그칠 때까지...
until the sun rises
해가 뜰 때까지
and the ground will dry up.
땅이 마르게 됩니다.
In Seoul now,
지금은 서울
it rains without warning.
예고 없이 비가 내립니다.
Is it a sign of sadness
슬픔의 표시인가
what does God send us?
하나님은 우리에게 무엇을 보내시나요?
You,
당신
did they bring umbrellas?
우산을 가져왔나요?
He also played Bom like this,
봄을 이렇게 연기하기도 했고,
and she stayed very still.
그리고 그녀는 아주 가만히 있었습니다.
I still remember how soft it was the back of his little head.
부드러웠던 기억이 아직도 나요 그의 작은 머리 뒤쪽.
The good memories
좋은 추억
They are the ones that make it more difficult.
그들은 그것을 더 어렵게 만드는 사람들입니다.
If I had known it would be like this,
이럴 줄 알았더라면,
I wouldn't have tried so hard.
나는 그렇게 열심히 노력하지 않았을 것이다.
Erase that package from your mind,
그 꾸러미를 마음에서 지우세요.
do you think it still exists?
아직도 존재한다고 생각하시나요?
Do you remember those travelers we saw in Jeju
제주에서 만난 여행자들을 기억하시나요?
when did we eat?
우리 언제 먹었어?
Jin Ho...
진호...
don't you hear that?
그거 안 들려?
The rain?
비?
Jun Kyung, where did you go?
준경아 어디갔어?
It's pouring.
쏟아지고 있어요.
You should have brought an umbrella.
우산을 가져왔어야 했는데.
The umbrellas always seem to be nearby,
우산은 언제나 가까이 있는 것 같지만,
but they are never there when you need them.
하지만 당신이 필요할 때 그들은 결코 거기에 있지 않습니다.
I lied to you.
나는 당신에게 거짓말을했습니다.
Before,
전에,
when we talk on the phone...
우리가 전화로 얘기할 때..
was with Yun Ju.
윤주랑 같이 있었어.
I thought it would make you uncomfortable...
불편할 줄 알았는데...
so I didn't say anything.
그래서 나는 아무 말도 하지 않았다.
I thought lying would be better.
거짓말을 하는 게 더 나을 것 같았다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I went to your studio before.
전에 당신 스튜디오에 갔던 적이 있어요.
Thanks for being honest with me.
나에게 솔직하게 말해줘서 고마워요.
I thought about it a lot...
많이 생각해봤는데...
and alone
그리고 혼자
I wish it was the right time.
적절한 시기였으면 좋겠습니다.
When you need me...
내가 필요할 때...
and when not...
그리고 그렇지 않을 때...
I will always be
나는 항상 그럴 것이다
at your side
당신 편에서
Jun Kyung...
준경...
would you marry me?
나랑 결혼해줄래?
- Hello, dad. - Hello.
- 안녕하세요, 아빠. - 안녕하세요.
Are you busy?
바쁘세요?
I'm fine. What's happening?
저는 괜찮아요. 무슨 일이야?
It's nothing serious.
심각한 일은 아닙니다.
It's about Ja Yeong.
자영에 관한 것입니다.
He seemed better after coming here,
여기 오고 나서 좋아진 것 같았는데,
but he's not sleeping well.
그런데 그 사람이 잠을 잘 못 자요.
She seems more nervous lately.
그녀는 요즘 더 긴장한 것 같습니다.
and a little sad.
그리고 조금 슬프다.
I heard there's something called pet loss syndrome.
라는 게 있다고 들었는데 애완동물 손실 증후군.
Maybe that's what's happening to you.
어쩌면 그것이 당신에게 일어나고 있는 일일 수도 있습니다.
Pet loss syndrome?
애완동물 손실 증후군?
Yes.
예.
Many people do therapy after losing a pet.
많은 사람들이 치료를 받습니다. 애완동물을 잃은 후.
After all, he lost his family.
결국 그는 가족을 잃었습니다.
TRUE.
진실.
Why don't you come visit her? with Do Hyun and Jun Seo?
그녀를 방문하는 게 어때요? 도현이랑 서준이랑?
I haven't seen you in a while.
나는 당신을 한동안 보지 못했습니다.
I also miss Daniel.
다니엘도 그리워요.
We'll go, dad.
우리 갈게요, 아빠.
I'm sorry I didn't call more.
더 이상 전화하지 못해서 미안해요.
I know you're busy. Thank you.
당신이 바쁘다는 걸 알아요. 감사합니다.
You are welcome.
물론이죠.
By the way...
그런데...
You're fine, right?
당신은 괜찮죠?
I'm fine.
잘 지내요.
Okay, see you soon.
알겠습니다. 곧 뵙겠습니다.
Yes.
그렇습니다.
Ja Yeong,
자영,
what are you looking at like that?
뭘 그렇게 보고 있어?
The five-day market should open today.
오늘부터 5일장이 열립니다.
Do you want to go see?
보러 갈래?
We can buy some things,
우리는 몇 가지 물건을 살 수 있고,
maybe eat jajangmyeon for a change.
기분전환으로 자장면을 먹어도 될 것 같아요.
Jin Ho.
진호.
Yeah?
응?
Coming here like this,
이렇게 오니까,
Don't you think it was too hasty?
너무 성급했다고 생각하지 않나요?
As if we were running away.
마치 우리가 도망가는 것처럼.
Jin Ho!
진호!
Hey.
여기요.
Don't you like this place?
이 장소가 마음에 들지 않나요?
- That? - Answer me.
- 저것? - 대답해 보세요.
Don't you like this place?
이 장소가 마음에 들지 않나요?
- It's not that... - You said it yourself.
- 그게 아니고... - 당신이 직접 말했어요.
You wanted to live in a place
당신은 그런 곳에서 살고 싶었어요
where were you first to see the flowers open,
너 처음에 어디 있었어? 꽃이 활짝 피는 모습을 보고,
to feel the sun on your face, in stepping on fallen leaves.
당신의 얼굴에 태양을 느끼기 위해, 낙엽을 밟으면서.
You said it.
당신이 말했잖아요.
We weren't running away.
우리는 도망치지 않았습니다.
I felt a little trapped.
조금 갇혀있는 느낌이 들었습니다.
I didn't think it through.
나는 그것을 깊이 생각하지 않았습니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I think I was too sensitive.
제가 너무 예민했던 것 같아요.
You and Jun Kyung live together, right?
너랑 준경이랑 같이 사는 거 맞지?
Which basically means who are already concubines.
기본적으로 의미하는 것은 이미 첩이 된 사람들.
You are only one step away.
당신은 단지 한 걸음 떨어져 있습니다.
Just one more step.
한 단계만 더 하면 됩니다.
This is hard for her now.
지금은 그녀에게 이것이 어렵다.
Clear.
분명한.
It's just...
그것은 단지 ...
my job is unstable
내 직업이 불안정해
- and I have a son. - It's like that.
- 그리고 나에겐 아들이 있어요. - 그렇군요.
If there is at least one percent of doubt behind a proposal,
1퍼센트라도 있으면 제안에 대한 의심,
It never feels good.
결코 기분이 좋지 않습니다.
It's not about her.
그녀에 관한 것이 아닙니다.
Isn't it because of the boy
그 애 때문 아닌가?
And it's not because of the boy's mother?
그리고 그것은 그 소년의 어머니 때문이 아닌가?
So what is it?
그래서 그것은 무엇입니까?
This is not your problem.
이것은 당신의 문제가 아닙니다.
For Jun Kyung,
준경씨에게
the marriage itself... you know?
결혼 그 자체... 알지?
How do I say it?
어떻게 말해야 하나요?
He's already thought about it a thousand times,
그는 이미 그것에 대해 수천 번이나 생각했습니다.
even all the wildest scenarios.
가장 거친 시나리오조차도.
That's what intelligent and pessimistic people do.
그것은 똑똑하고 비관적인 사람들이 하는 일이다.
The point
요점
It's not about you or anyone else.
그것은 당신이나 다른 사람에 관한 것이 아닙니다.
Jun Kyung has something,
준경이 뭔가가 있어
an obsession that can never fail.
결코 실패할 수 없는 집착.
Kind of like perfectionism, basically.
기본적으로 완벽주의와 비슷합니다.
It's for me.
그것은 나를 위한 것입니다.
Difficult to understand, isn't it?
이해하기 어렵죠?
Yes.
예.
I really don't understand it
정말 이해가 안 돼요
and I don't identify myself at all.
그리고 나는 내 자신을 전혀 밝히지 않습니다.
Do Hyun is a good guy, really.
도현이는 정말 좋은 사람이에요.
showed me
나에게 보여주었다
that happiness comes from being with someone.
그 행복은 누군가와 함께 있는 것에서 옵니다.
What is the problem?
문제는 무엇입니까?
I don't feel safe.
나는 안전하다고 느끼지 않는다.
Dealing with what I already know is overwhelming.
내가 이미 알고 있는 것을 다루는 것은 압도적이다.
If something unexpected happens between us,
우리 사이에 예상치 못한 일이 생기면
some disaster that we cannot control...
통제할 수 없는 재난…
I know I would want to run away.
나는 도망치고 싶어한다는 것을 안다.
Yes.
예.
It must have been difficult for your dad, right?
아빠도 힘들었을 텐데요, 그렇죠?
No.
아니요.
I think my mom had it worse.
내 생각엔 엄마가 더 심했던 것 같아.
He couldn't hold on, he couldn't let go.
그는 버틸 수도 없었고, 놓아줄 수도 없었습니다.
I think he suffered more.
내 생각엔 그 사람이 더 많은 고통을 겪었던 것 같아.
How serious is it?
얼마나 심각한가요?
A total collapse.
완전한 붕괴.
And Jun Kyung?
그리고 준경이?
It's sincere.
진심이에요.
Enough to give up a diamond.
다이아몬드를 포기하기에 충분합니다.
I never saw Do Hyun so serious.
도현이가 그렇게 진지한 모습을 본 적이 없었다.
You won't think
당신은 생각하지 않을 것입니다
They are going to separate, right?
그들은 헤어질 거예요, 그렇죠?
A couple that went out enough, at the right age,
충분히 나간 커플, 적절한 나이에,
but can't take the next step?
그런데 다음 단계로 나아갈 수 없나요?
Yes, that happens.
예, 그런 일이 발생합니다.
Even though they are clearly in love?
분명히 사랑에 빠졌는데도요?
Love is supposed to end in marriage.
사랑은 결혼으로 끝나야 합니다.
That's how social animals are.
사회적 동물이 그렇습니다.
Love and marriage go together.
사랑과 결혼은 함께 가는 것입니다.
That's legit.
그것은 합법적입니다.
If someone is not the one to be with you,
누군가가 그 사람이 아니라면 당신과 함께하기 위해,
instinct drives you to find to someone who is.
본능이 당신을 찾게 만든다 그런 사람에게.
Does this really hurt you?
이게 정말 당신에게 상처를 주나요?
No.
아니요.
Maybe a little.
어쩌면 조금.
Just a little.
조금만.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Believe...
믿다...
that your time will come.
당신의 시간이 올 것이라고.
I will wait for it
나는 그것을 기다릴 것이다
with an open heart.
열린 마음으로.
Gracias
그라시아스
to understand.
이해하다.
This is completely rotten.
이것은 완전히 썩었습니다.
Wow, you scared me.
와, 겁먹었구나.
Can you do this?
당신은 이것을 할 수 있습니까?
You've never done it.
당신은 그것을 한 적이 없습니다.
Shouldn't we call someone?
누군가에게 전화하면 안 되나요?
It's our house. We can't call people all the time.
우리 집이에요. 우리는 항상 사람들에게 전화할 수는 없습니다.
I'll take care of it.
내가 처리할게.
- Do you want help? - No, it's okay.
- 도움을 원하시나요? - 아뇨, ​​괜찮아요.
It's dangerous, get off.
위험해요, 내리세요.
Get off.
내리세요.
It's dangerous.
위험해요.
Are you still angry?
아직도 화가 났나요?
Who says I'm angry?
내가 화가 났다고 누가 그래?
Just get off.
그냥 내리세요.
OK.
좋아요.
Who do you take me for?
당신은 나를 누구로 생각합니까?
I'll fix it perfectly.
완벽하게 고쳐드리겠습니다.
This is nothing.
이것은 아무것도 아니다.
How strong.
얼마나 강한가.
This is easy.
이것은 쉽습니다.
Gosh, it hurts!
맙소사, 아파요!
- Are you OK? - Wait.
- 괜찮으세요? - 기다리다.
Ja Yeong, help me! I shot myself.
자영아, 도와줘! 나는 나 자신을 쐈다.
It hurts me.
마음이 아프다.
- God! - No, what do we do?
- 하나님! - 아니, 우리 어떡하지?
No, don't go up.
아니, 올라가지 마세요.
Come down, I'll take care of it.
내려오세요. 제가 처리하겠습니다.
Don't throw!
던지지 마세요!
Hey, don't touch!
이봐, 만지지 마!
Did you just laugh?
방금 웃었나요?
I'm sorry,
미안해요
you look very...
너 정말 좋아 보여...
I can't with this.
난 이걸 할 수 없어.
Health!
건강!
Do you feel lighter now?
이제 좀 가벼워진 것 같나요?
You did very well.
당신은 아주 잘 했어요.
I wanted to treat you to something better.
나는 당신에게 더 나은 것을 대접하고 싶었습니다.
Every time I write late at night,
밤늦게 글을 쓸 때마다
I'm craving a seafood pancake.
나는 해산물 팬케이크를 먹고 싶어.
I tell myself I'll eat it the next day. and then I forget.
다음날 먹겠다고 다짐합니다. 그러다가 잊어버렸어요.
And every night, I think about it again.
그리고 매일 밤 나는 그것에 대해 다시 생각합니다.
You look very happy.
당신은 매우 행복해 보인다.
There seems to be good news.
좋은 소식이 있을 것 같습니다.
Is it so obvious?
너무 뻔한가요?
I don't want to be conceited.
나는 자만하고 싶지 않습니다.
My boyfriend is not a teacher,
내 남자친구는 선생님이 아니다.
but it seems that soon he will teach in a university.
하지만 곧 가르칠 것 같아 대학에서.
Double good news!
두배 좋은 소식!
I thought you already found out.
나는 당신이 이미 알고 있다고 생각했습니다.
About what?
무엇에 대해서?
Very good.
매우 좋은.
I chose the materials for the sophomore class.
제가 선택한 재료는 2학년을 위해.
I'm still organizing the third year.
아직 3년째 정리 중이에요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I found out from Professor Choi.
최교수님께서 알아봤습니다.
Congratulations.
축하해요.
It's thanks to you.
당신 덕분이에요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
The semester is almost over, so do it hard.
학기가 거의 끝나가는데, 그러니 열심히 하세요.
- OK. - Yes, finish everything and go.
- 좋아요. - 네, 다 끝내고 가세요.
If you need anything while you prepare for classes
수업을 준비하면서 필요한 것이 있다면
or have questions, come see me whenever you want.
질문이 있으시면 언제든지 저를 만나러 오세요.
Teacher.
선생님.
Yeah?
응?
Well...
음...
Be brief, I have a class soon.
간단히 말해서, 곧 수업이 있어요.
No, it's nothing.
아니요, 아무것도 아닙니다.
I will do my best until the end.
끝까지 최선을 다하겠습니다.
- Great, go ahead! - Yes.
- 좋아요, 계속하세요! - 예.
Hello, it's me.
안녕하세요, 나예요.
I have a quick question.
빠른 질문이 있습니다.
Sure, go ahead.
물론입니다.
Nowadays, if you want to be attached,
요즘은 애착을 갖고 싶다면
Do you still have to pay the supervising teacher?
아직도 감독 교사에게 돈을 지불해야 합니까?
That? That doesn't happen anymore.
저것? 그런 일은 더 이상 일어나지 않습니다.
Because?
왜냐하면?
It wasn't Professor Song, right?
송 교수님 아니셨죠?
No, someone just asked me.
아니요, 방금 누군가가 나에게 물었습니다.
Thanks,
감사합니다.
I'll call you later.
나중에 전화할게요.
Yeah.
응.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Jun Seo!
서준!
- Get up, come on. - Because?
- 일어나, 어서. - 왜냐하면?
Get up, give me your hand.
일어나서 손을 내밀어 주세요.
Because?
왜냐하면?
What's happening?
무슨 일이야?
Our mouthy writer says...
우리의 입담이 작가는 말합니다 ...
- Yes? - that I...
- 응? - 내가...
I won the grand prize!
제가 대상을 받았어요!
Oh really?
오, 진짜?
In the publisher's contest,
출판사 공모전에서는
I won first prize!
제가 1등상을 받았어요!
- I can't believe it! - You deserve it.
- 믿을 수가 없어요! - 당신은 그럴 자격이 있어요.
- Well done. - I'm very happy!
- 잘하셨어요. - 정말 기뻐요!
Did you pack your toothbrush and towel?
칫솔과 수건은 챙겨오셨나요?
Yes, I packed everything.
응, 다 챙겼어.
You said you wanted to go camping. Just in time.
캠핑을 가고 싶다고 하셨어요. 제때에.
Yes.
예.
Jun Seo and Hye On are very funny.
준서와 혜온은 정말 재미있습니다.
What are you going to do, mom?
뭘 할 거예요, 엄마?
You will be alone at home.
당신은 집에 혼자있을 것입니다.
I have a lot to do.
나는 할 일이 많다.
I'll see my friends and have fun.
친구들을 만나서 재미있게 놀겠습니다.
Mother.
어머니.
Even so,
비록 그렇다 하더라도,
don't forget
잊지 마세요
feed Oscar.
오스카에게 먹이를 주세요.
Do you think I would forget to feed Oscar?
내가 오스카에게 먹이 주는 것을 잊어버릴 것 같나요?
No, it's just that,
아니, 그냥 그래요
in fact, once,
사실 한 번은,
I skipped his meal on purpose...
일부러 식사를 건너뛰었는데...
because I didn't like it
내가 싫었으니까
Jun Kyung.
준경.
I think dad arrived.
아빠가 도착한 것 같아요.
- Leave. - Have fun.
- 떠나다. - 재미있게 보내세요.
You are washing my face
당신은 내 얼굴을 씻고 있습니다
and the hair.
그리고 머리카락.
You're spoiling me.
당신은 나를 망치고 있어요.
Getting hurt has its benefits.
상처를 입는 것에는 장점이 있습니다.
Maybe I should hurt my right hand next time.
어쩌면 오른손을 다쳐야 할지도 몰라 다음 번에.
Then you would feed me too, right?
그럼 나한테도 먹여줄 거지?
Can you stop talking?
그만 얘기하면 안 돼요?
They will arrive at any moment.
그들은 언제든지 도착할 것입니다.
Okay, rinsing.
알았어, 씻어.
It feels good, doesn't it?
기분 좋지 않나요?
- Dad! - Thank you for coming here.
- 아빠! - 와주셔서 감사합니다.
- Hello.
- 안녕하세요.
Wow, you've grown a lot.
와, 많이 컸구나.
Catch him, catch him.
잡아라, 잡아라.
Did you catch one?
하나 잡았나요?
Jun Kyung!
준경!
Look at this.
이것 좀 보세요.
There are many fish, but he can't catch any.
물고기도 많고, 하지만 그는 아무것도 잡을 수 없습니다.
How can you fail with so many?
이렇게 많은데 어떻게 실패할 수 있나요?
Seriously, why can't you catch one?
진심으로, 왜 한 마리도 잡을 수 없나요?
The more I see Do Hyun...
도현이 볼수록..
But I think he's a very good guy.
하지만 내 생각엔 그 사람은 정말 좋은 사람인 것 같아.
Do you think so too?
당신도 그렇게 생각하나요?
Yes.
예.
They look very good together.
그들은 아주 좋아 보인다.
So why do you hesitate?
그렇다면 왜 주저합니까?
Jun Kyung.
준경.
Not everything was difficult for me.
나에게 모든 것이 어려운 것은 아니었습니다.
Maybe you don't know it yet.
어쩌면 당신은 아직 그것을 모르고 있습니다.
That's why
그렇기 때문에
you are afraid,
당신은 두려워
but someday you will understand.
하지만 언젠가는 이해하게 될 거예요.
Love is not just being happy
사랑은 단지 행복하기만 한 것이 아니다
and have fun together.
그리고 함께 즐거운 시간을 보내세요.
Sometimes it's feeling tenderness...
때로는 부드러움도 느껴집니다..
worry.
걱정.
That is also love.
그것도 사랑입니다.
I was happy...
나는 행복했다 ...
and I was grateful for everything.
그리고 나는 모든 것에 감사했습니다.
I'm sorry you saw the part of me...
내 모습을 본 것 같아 미안해...
who wanted to let go...
누가 버리고 싶었는데...
that I wanted to escape.
탈출하고 싶었다는 것.
Jun Kyung,
준경,
don't be afraid.
두려워하지 마십시오.
You are much stronger
당신은 훨씬 더 강하다
that me
그 나
I caught one!
하나 잡았어요!
I have it! Good!
나는 그것을 가지고있다! 좋은!
Jun Kyung!
준경!
- Look at this. - We caught a lot!
- 이것 좀 보세요. - 많이 잡았어요!
Okay.
알겠습니다.
Let's find hope that anxiety tried to hide.
희망을 찾자 그 불안은 숨기려고 노력했습니다.
Even if it doesn't turn out as I imagine,
내 생각대로 되지 않더라도
I won't be disappointed.
실망하지 않을 거예요.
I chose to trust myself.
나는 나 자신을 믿기로 결정했습니다.
And as soon as I decided that...
그리고 결정하자마자...
I realized.
나는 깨달았다.
Of what...
무슨...
were you so afraid?
그렇게 무서웠나요?
- Did you eat two peppers? - Be careful, it's spicy.
- 고추 두 개 먹었어? - 조심하세요, 매워요.
Did you eat it?
먹었나요?
My God.
맙소사.
I have something to say.
할 말이 있어요.
I'm going to get married
나는 결혼할 거예요
with Do Hyun.
도현이랑.
If you were going to say yes anyway,
어차피 그렇다고 대답할 거라면,
Why didn't you do it from the beginning?
왜 처음부터 하지 않았나요?
you know how difficult
얼마나 어려운지 알잖아
which was for me.
그것은 나를 위한 것이었다.
Back then, those feelings were real.
그 당시에는 그 감정이 진짜였습니다.
And what happened...
그리고 무슨 일이 일어났나요...
with those feelings?
그런 감정으로?
Well, greed?
음, 탐욕?
That diamond ring caught my attention.
그 다이아몬드 반지가 내 눈길을 끌었다.
No matter how much you think about it,
아무리 생각해도,
there is not a single reason
이유는 하나도 없어
so as not to marry you.
너랑 결혼하지 않으려면.
Ju Do Hyun...
주도현...
would you marry me?
나랑 결혼해줄래?
Wait.
기다리다.
Are you proposing to me?
나한테 프로포즈하는 거야?
Yes.
예.
I want to marry you...
나는 당신과 결혼하고 싶습니다 ...
Jun Kyung.
준경.
I miss those days.
그 시절이 그리워요.
After a performance, You walked me to the door.
공연이 끝난 후, 당신은 나를 문까지 데려갔습니다.
That is the job of a representative.
그것이 대표의 일입니다.
So what is it like?
그럼 어떤가요?
You had a reason to go to Korea. How's that going?
한국에 갈 이유가 있었어요. 잘 지내요?
It's not easy.
쉽지 않습니다.
Why?
왜?
Wasn't that something you wanted very much?
그게 너무 갖고 싶었던 거 아니었나요?
Maybe someone else wants it too.
어쩌면 다른 사람도 그것을 원할 수도 있습니다.
Yun Ju,
윤주
you said you couldn't breathe here.
여기서는 숨을 쉴 수 없다고 하더군요.
You left to survive.
당신은 살아남기 위해 떠났습니다.
What are you doing?
뭐하고 있어요?
It's your birthday, and you're drinking alone?
생일인데 혼자 술을 마시고 계시나요?
I miss you, Anna.
보고 싶어, 안나.
You can come back whenever you want.
원하시면 언제든지 다시 오실 수 있습니다.
You also have family here.
여기에는 가족도 있습니다.
Yo.
요.
Thanks, Anna.
고마워요, 안나.
Daniel...
다니엘...
what did you think?
어떻게 생각했어?
It was fun.
재미있었습니다.
No,
아니요,
not that.
그렇지 않습니다.
that I
내가
me case
나 사건
con Jun Kyung.
사기꾼 준경.
Bueno,
부에노,
I think I agree.
나는 동의한다고 생각합니다.
Mom will be fine too.
엄마도 괜찮을 거예요.
Should we...
우리는 ...
hide it from him for now?
지금은 그 사람한테 숨기라고?
Yeah.
응.
GOOD.
좋은.
About that...
그것에 대해 ...
I'll tell you myself.
내가 직접 말해주지.
Congratulations,
축하해요,
dad.
아빠.
I'm sorry I didn't tell you sooner.
더 일찍 말하지 못해 미안해요.
Thank you for taking care of Jun Seo.
서준씨를 챙겨주셔서 감사합니다.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
They could sleep in the bed.
그들은 침대에서 잘 수 있었습니다.
I love it, I'll sleep here.
너무 좋아 여기서 자겠습니다.
Well, then, I'll sleep with you.
그럼, 난 당신과 함께 자겠습니다.
It seems like a trip with my best friends.
친한 친구들과 여행을 가는 것 같아요.
Yeah.
응.
Tonight seems like one of those nights
오늘 밤도 그런 밤 중 하나인 것 같아
that we will remember for a long time.
우리가 오랫동안 기억할 것입니다.
I hate to see it end like this.
이대로 끝나는 건 보기 싫다.
So,
그래서,
Let's not finish it.
끝내지 말자.
Yeah?
응?
So how about
그렇다면 어떨까요?
one more beer each?
맥주 한 잔 더?
- I'm in. - I'm coming.
- 들어왔어 - 내가 간다.
Well, I'll go get them!
글쎄, 내가 가서 사올게!
Dad, are you still awake?
아빠, 아직 안 자셨어요?
I can't sleep.
잠이 안 와요.
¿You?
너?
Me neither.
나도 마찬가지다.
Why are you awake?
왜 깨어 있나요?
Looks like we won't be sleeping anytime soon.
우리는 곧 잠을 자지 못할 것 같습니다.
We entertained ourselves by talking.
우리는 이야기를 나누며 즐거운 시간을 보냈습니다.
Weren't you going to take them?
가져갈 생각은 아니었어?
There is more.
더 많은 것이 있습니다.
- Health.
- 건강.
Congratulations.
축하해요.
I heard you're teaching next semester.
다음 학기에 강의하신다고 들었어요.
Hye On couldn't stop bragging.
혜온은 자랑을 멈추지 못했다.
Yeah...
응...
gracias.
그라시아스.
You look more adult.
좀 더 어른스러워 보이시네요.
I thought you would make fun of Do Hyun,
도현을 놀릴 줄 알았는데,
saying he would regret it to marry me or something.
후회할 거라고 말했어 나랑 결혼하자든가.
Am I a child or what?
나는 어린아이인가?
Before,
전에,
I worried about things like this.
이런 것들이 걱정됐어요.
Jun Kyung
준경
She was beautiful, intelligent and had everything,
그녀는 아름다웠고, 똑똑했고, 모든 것을 다 갖고 있었습니다.
but I was worried that I wouldn't have met the right person.
하지만 난 그게 걱정됐어 제대로 된 사람을 못 만났을 거예요.
And as for Jun Seo,
그리고 서준의 경우,
He was handsome and kind,
잘생겼고 친절했고,
but I was worried that I hadn't found what he really loved to do.
하지만 내가 찾지 못했을까봐 걱정됐어 그가 정말 좋아했던 일.
It turns out
그것은 밝혀졌다
that everything was a useless worry.
모든 것이 쓸데없는 걱정이었다는 걸.
Congratulations, my daughter.
축하해요, 내 딸.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Jun Seo, keep giving it your all.
서준아, 계속 최선을 다해라.
OK.
좋아요.
I am very grateful to both of them.
두 분 모두에게 정말 감사드립니다.
I didn't do much for you.
나는 당신을 위해 많은 일을 하지 않았습니다.
On a night like this,
이런 밤에는,
I wish his mom was here with us.
그의 엄마가 우리와 함께 있었으면 좋았을 텐데요.
Please check your account and balance
계좌 및 잔액을 확인하세요
and select a transaction.
거래를 선택합니다.
[Balance: 260,000 won]
[잔액 : 260,000원]
Remove your card.
카드를 제거하세요.
[24 hour ATM]
[24시간 ATM]
Make sure you have all your belongings.
모든 소지품을 가지고 있는지 확인하세요.
Thank you for using our service.
저희 서비스를 이용해 주셔서 감사합니다.
[Cash Advance Withdrawal]
[현금선지급출금]
[Withdrawal amount: 5,000,000 won]
[출금금액 : 5,000,000원]
[Department of Media Studies, Professor Choi Sung Min]
[미디어학과, 최성민 교수]
We came here a lot when Jun Seo was little.
우리는 준서가 어렸을 때 여기에 자주 왔었어요.
The soup here is amazing.
여기 수프는 훌륭합니다.
Oh really?
오, 진짜?
Let's sit here.
여기 앉자.
Jun Kyung?
준경?
Chang Sik? So long!
창식? 그럼 또!
- How have you been? - Yes...
- 잘 지냈어요? - 네...
Who is he?
그는 누구입니까?
It's...
그것은 ...
my boyfriend,
내 남자친구,
we are going to get married.
우리는 결혼할 예정이에요.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Did Jun Kyung ever tell you about me?
준경이가 나에 대해 말한 적 있어?
He said he had a partner who became a priest.
파트너가 있다고 하더군요 신부가 된 사람.
Just "a companion"?
그냥 "동반자"인가요?
Yes.
예.
I guess...
아마도...
who loves you very much, Do Jun.
너를 정말 사랑하는 사람, 도준.
I'm Do Hyun. Ju Do Hyun.
저는 도현이에요. 주도현.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
He seems to love you very much,
그 사람이 당신을 무척 사랑하는 것 같군요.
Do Hyun.
도현.
He just called me an ex-colleague.
그는 방금 나를 전 동료라고 불렀습니다.
Because, of course,
물론,
Maybe you don't need to know everything.
어쩌면 모든 것을 알 필요는 없을 수도 있습니다.
Yes, it's better.
예, 더 좋습니다.
It's better not to know too much.
너무 많이 알지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
- Here you go. - Thank you.
- 여기요. - 감사합니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I won't let another priest officiate the wedding.
다른 신부가 결혼식 주례를 하게 하지 않겠습니다.
What are you taking about?
당신은 무엇을 복용하고 있습니까?
Your wedding will be in our church, yes or yes.
당신의 결혼식은 우리 교회에서 열릴 것입니다. 예, 그렇습니다.
That's great for me.
그것은 나에게 좋은 일이다.
You know, it's hard to book places nowadays.
요즘은 예약하기 힘든 거 아시죠?
- Hello. -Won Young?
- 안녕하세요. -원영?
I just moved to this neighborhood.
방금 이 동네로 이사왔어요.
Oh really? Excellent.
오, 진짜? 훌륭한.
He is the priest of the local church.
그는 지역 교회의 목사이다.
He is my former classmate.
그는 나의 전 동급생입니다.
And he is my boyfriend.
그리고 그는 내 남자 친구입니다.
Nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
But...
하지만...
You look very familiar to me.
당신은 나에게 매우 친숙해 보입니다.
Yes.
예.
I also feel like I've seen you before.
나도 예전에 당신을 본 것 같은 느낌이 듭니다.
- In a minimarket... - Do you have a criminal record?
- 미니마켓에서... - 범죄기록이 있나요?
I don't even know if that pork chop
돼지갈비인지도 모르겠는데
It got into my mouth or nose.
입이나 코에 들어갔습니다.
If I screw up even a little here,
여기서 조금이라도 실수하면
I will be in serious trouble.
나는 심각한 문제에 빠질 것이다.
Are you just realizing it?
방금 깨닫고 계시나요?
I don't know if I should get married like this.
이런 식으로 결혼해야 할지 모르겠어요.
So, cancel it.
그러니 취소하세요.
Hey, I can't do that.
이봐, 난 그럴 수 없어.
Our future is there.
우리의 미래는 거기에 있습니다.
You are funny.
당신은 재밌어요.
So for our second,
그래서 우리 두 번째로,
Do you want a boy or a girl?
당신은 소년을 원합니까, 아니면 소녀를 원합니까?
What is this, out of nowhere?
갑자기 이게 뭐죠?
I prefer the second one to be a girl,
나는 둘째가 여자인 것을 더 좋아한다.
and then a child.
그리고 아이.
Who decided that there is a "later"?
"나중에"가 있다고 누가 결정했습니까?
We agree on at least one thing.
우리는 적어도 한 가지에 동의합니다.
The second is a girl.
두 번째는 소녀입니다.
Who agrees?
누가 동의하나요?
I? No no.
나? 아니 아니.
Jin Ho,
진호,
Are you almost done?
거의 다 됐나요?
One second,
1초,
I'm almost there.
거의 다 왔어요.
This feels very uncomfortable.
이것은 매우 불편한 느낌입니다.
Come out now. I'll tell you how you look.
지금 나오세요. 당신이 어떻게 보이는지 말씀 드리겠습니다.
It's strange, isn't it?
이상하지 않나요?
Yes, it's weird.
응, 이상해.
Good.
좋은.
Is something wrong?
뭔가 문제가 있나요?
Come on, hurry up, I feel uncomfortable.
자, 서둘러요. 불편해요.
I feel very uncomfortable, hurry up.
매우 불편합니다. 서둘러주세요.
Well, wait.
잠깐만요.
I'm coming.
나는 간다.
Simple happiness
단순한 행복
sometimes it fills us...
때때로 우리를 가득 채웁니다...
before we know it.
우리가 알기 전에
Surprise.
놀람.
Live as always, each one in his place,
늘 그렇듯이 각자 자기 자리에서 생활하세요.
it was enough...
충분했어요...
to feel complete.
완전함을 느끼기 위해
I didn't expect,
예상하지 못했습니다.
I didn't even have hope for anything else.
다른 어떤 것에도 희망이 없었습니다.
But life
하지만 인생
has a way of putting
퍼팅하는 방법이 있습니다
the most unexpected moments in front of us.
우리 앞에 가장 예상치 못한 순간이 있습니다.
My period was late, so I thought maybe...
생리가 늦어졌는데, 그래서 아마도...
Are you disappointed?
실망하셨나요?
I guess I had a little hope...
약간의 희망은 있었던 것 같은데...
but now that it is like this,
하지만 지금은 이렇기 때문에
I'm more worried than disappointed.
실망보다는 걱정이 더 큽니다.
There is no rush.
서두르지 마세요.
We haven't even had the wedding.
우리는 결혼식도 치르지 않았어요.
Sincerely,
진심으로,
I haven't tried that hard.
나는 그렇게 열심히 노력하지 않았습니다.
If I really try...
만약 내가 정말로 노력한다면...
But what if...?
하지만 만약...?
And
그리고
if something happens to me?
나에게 무슨 일이 생기면?
What could happen to you?
당신에게 무슨 일이 일어날 수 있나요?
I am an obstetrician and gynecologist.
저는 산부인과 의사이자 산부인과 의사입니다.
I am 38 years old
나는 38세입니다
and it would be my first pregnancy.
그리고 그것은 나의 첫 임신이 될 것입니다.
Should we
우리는
have us checked, just in case?
만일을 대비해서 확인해 볼까요?
In our hospital? It would be uncomfortable.
우리 병원에서요? 불편할 것입니다.
So, we'll go somewhere else.
그래서 우리는 다른 곳으로 갈 것입니다.
We will go together and they will check us together.
우리는 함께 갈 것이고 그들은 우리를 함께 확인할 것입니다.
Why you? You don't have any problem.
왜요? 당신에게는 아무런 문제가 없습니다.
That's what couples do.
커플이 하는 일이 바로 그것이다.
They go together.
그들은 함께 간다.
It's a mountain road, so it gets dark fast.
산길인데, 그래서 빨리 어두워집니다.
Be careful when coming.
오실 때 조심하세요.
OK.
좋아요.
Thank God.
하느님 감사합니다.
The number you dialed is not...
당신이 전화한 번호는...
What is she so involved in that she can't answer?
그녀는 무슨 일에 그렇게 연루되어 대답할 수 없는 걸까요?
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Where are you?
당신은 어디에 있나요?
At university, obviously.
대학에서는 당연히요.
Are you staying late again?
또 늦게까지 계시나요?
The teacher He got the research grant, remember?
선생님 그 사람 연구 보조금 받았잖아, 기억나?
He asked me to help him until the end.
그는 나에게 끝까지 도와달라고 부탁했다.
The teacher is calling me.
선생님이 나를 부르고 있어요.
I'll be late tonight, so go to bed first.
나 오늘 밤 늦을 거야, 그러니 먼저 자러 가세요.
Bye bye.
안녕.
Yes, I am in this square now.
네, 저는 지금 이 광장에 있습니다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
- Hey, hurry up. - Just one more.
- 이봐, 서둘러. - 하나만 더요.
One more drink.
한 잔 더.
- Over there, to the car. - I have it.
- 저기 차로요. - 갖고 있어요.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
The number you dialed is out of service.
당신이 거신 전화번호는 서비스가 종료된 번호입니다.
Ha Yeong!
하영!
Why weren't you answering the phone? I looked for you.
왜 전화를 받지 않았나요? 나는 당신을 찾았습니다.
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
Ja Yeong.
자영.
Hey.
여기요.
Are you OK?
괜찮으세요?
I don't know where I am.
나는 내가 어디에 있는지 모른다.
suddenly
갑자기
I don't remember what I was doing here.
내가 여기서 무엇을 했는지 기억이 나지 않습니다.
I got very scared.
나는 매우 무서워졌습니다.
I thought I had to go home.
집에 가야 한다고 생각했어요.
I had to come back to you...
난 당신에게 다시 와야 했어요...
but I don't know where I am
하지만 내가 어디에 있는지 모르겠어요
nor how to get home.
집에 가는 방법도.
Alright.
괜찮은.
I'm sorry,
미안해요
I arrived late.
나는 늦게 도착했다.
It's dark, that's all.
어두워요. 그게 다예요.
The road is dark, The trees look the same.
길은 어둡고, 나무도 똑같아 보입니다.
- Anyone would be confused. - No.
- 누구라도 헷갈릴 것 같아요. - 아니.
I told you
내가 말했잖아
I loved this forest after we moved here.
나는 이 숲을 사랑했다 우리가 여기로 이사한 후.
I walked here every day.
나는 매일 여기를 걸었다.
How could...?
어떻게...?
How could I not know?
내가 어떻게 모를 수 있겠는가?
Your results look good.
결과가 좋아 보입니다.
Getting pregnant shouldn't be difficult.
임신하는 것은 어렵지 않을 것입니다.
Oh really? What a relief.
오, 진짜? 정말 다행이네요.
See? I told you it would be fine.
보다? 나는 괜찮을 것이라고 말했다.
but
하지만
about his results, Ju Do Hyun...
유도현 결과에 대해...
Yes?
응?
I am afraid that its result
그 결과가 두려워요
It was negative.
부정적이었습니다.
Negative?
부정적인?
What does that mean?
그게 무슨 뜻이에요?
It means infertility.
불임이라는 뜻입니다.
It just can't be.
그럴 수 없습니다.
Of course, nothing is 100% certain.
물론 100% 확실한 것은 없습니다.
We...
우리는...
I mean,
내 말은,
I already have a son.
나는 이미 아들이 있습니다.
Yeah?
응?
Your hormone levels are quite low.
호르몬 수치가 상당히 낮습니다.
Depending on your FSH levels,
FSH 수준에 따라,
It appears to be non-obstructive azoospermia.
비폐쇄성 무정자증인 것으로 보입니다.
Non-obstructive means it is congenital.
비폐쇄성이란 선천적이라는 의미입니다.
Are you sure?
확실합니까?
As I said, there is no absolute security.
내가 말했듯이 절대적인 보안은 없습니다.
A genetic test would be the definitive step.
유전자 검사가 최종 단계가 될 것입니다.
If it were me,
나라면,
I would talk to the child's mother.
나는 그 아이의 엄마와 이야기를 나누겠다.
Do Hyun.
도현.
I'm going in.
나는 들어갈 것이다.
I'm sorry.
미안해요.
I guess I didn't hear you.
내가 당신 말을 듣지 못한 것 같아요.
I'm sorry. Because of me...
죄송합니다. 나 때문에...
Don't say that.
그렇게 말하지 마세요.
Daniel
다니엘
It's my son.
내 아들이에요.
I won't review anything else.
다른 건 검토하지 않겠습니다.
There's no need.
필요하지 않습니다.
we can act as if none of this had happened.
우리는 행동할 수 있어요 마치 아무 일도 일어나지 않은 것처럼.
nothing happened,
아무 일도 일어나지 않았어
as long as no one knows...
아무도 모르는 한...
right?
그렇죠?
Daniel...
다니엘...
It's my son.
내 아들이에요.
Yes,
네,
Daniel is your son.
다니엘은 당신의 아들입니다.
Promise me, Jun Kyung.
약속해 준경아.
That no one...
그 누구도...
You will find out about today.
오늘 알게 될 것입니다.
Yes.
예.
It will be fine if no one knows.
아무도 몰라도 괜찮을 것입니다.
[Pianist Im Yun Ju]
[피아니스트 임윤주]
Im Yun Ju,
임윤주,
I was wondering What would be your first official move?
나는 궁금했다 첫 번째 공식적인 움직임은 무엇입니까?
back to Korea.
한국으로 돌아갑니다.
I didn't expect it to be a commercial.
광고일 거라고는 예상하지 못했어요.
Who was contacted first?
먼저 연락한 사람은 누구였나요?
You or Do Hyun?
당신인가, 도현인가?
Does that matter?
그게 중요합니까?
We are not strangers.
우리는 낯선 사람이 아닙니다.
We are also no strangers to Do Hyun,
우리도 도현이 낯설지 않고,
but he never asked us for favors like that.
하지만 그 사람은 우리에게 그런 부탁을 한 적이 없어요.
Hey, we're not like her.
이봐요, 우리는 그 사람과 달라요.
But still, are you okay?
그런데 그래도 괜찮으세요?
About what?
무엇에 대해서?
I heard that Do Hyun is getting married.
도현이 결혼한다는 소식을 들었어요.
Who told you that?
누가 그런 말을 했나요?
Jung Hoon.
정훈.
I spoke with him a few days ago.
저는 며칠 전에 그와 이야기를 나눴습니다.
You didn't know?
몰랐나요?
So you're getting married.
그래서 당신은 결혼합니다.
It doesn't seem like you came to congratulate me.
축하해주러 온 것 같지는 않네요.
What do you want?
당신은 무엇을 원하세요?
I'm thinking of trying it.
시도해 볼 생각입니다.
Try what?
무엇을 시도할까요?
I'm moving to this neighborhood.
저는 이 동네로 이사해요.
That?
저것?
I already found a place,
이미 장소를 찾았는데,
I'm moving next month.
다음 달에 이사해요.
Sincerely,
진심으로,
Marriage is not that big a deal.
결혼은 그리 대단한 일이 아니다.
Know? Do Hyun and I broke up despite Daniel.
알다? 도현이랑 헤어졌어 다니엘에도 불구하고.
And it hasn't happened yet.
그리고 아직 그런 일은 일어나지 않았습니다.
What exactly are you trying to do?
정확히 무엇을 하려는 건가요?
If you were me, what would you do?
당신이 나라면 어떻게 하시겠습니까?
If you can't win anyway,
어차피 이길 수 없다면,
Wouldn't you want to destroy everything?
모든 것을 파괴하고 싶지 않으신가요?
Do you think feelings are a game?
감정이 게임이라고 생각하시나요?
If Daniel lived closer to his dad, I would be very happy.
다니엘이 아버지와 더 가까이 살았다면, 나는 매우 행복할 것입니다.
By Daniel,
다니엘로,
I would make an even more selfish decision.
나는 더욱 이기적인 결정을 내릴 것이다.
You don't even know what Do Hyun thinks.
도현이가 무슨 생각을 하는지도 모르시는군요.
I would definitely be happy if your son moved nearby.
분명 행복할 텐데 당신의 아들이 근처로 이사했다면.
I wanted to ask you something.
나는 당신에게 뭔가를 물어보고 싶었습니다.
Is Daniel really Do Hyun's son?
다니엘이 정말 도현 아들인가요?
That?
저것?
Is Daniel your biological son?
다니엘이 친아들인가요?
I will only become more famous,
나는 더욱 유명해질 것이다
even better.
더 좋습니다.
If that happens, the pressure will be on you.
그런 일이 발생하면 압박감이 가중될 것입니다.
I have no intention of congratulating you.
축하할 생각은 없습니다.
You do this
당신은 이것을 합니다
because you want to break up with me, right?
너 나랑 헤어지고 싶어서 그러는 거 맞지?
Idiot.
바보.
Don't worry,
걱정하지 마세요.
we just came to make sure that everything is fine.
우리는 단지 확인하러 왔습니다 다 괜찮다고.
I really wanted you to be happy.
당신이 행복하길 진심으로 바랐습니다.
I thought I would be happy with you too.
나도 당신과 함께라면 행복할 거라고 생각했어요.
But I don't think I can.
하지만 그럴 수 없을 것 같아요.
Do you really believe that?
정말로 그렇게 믿으시나요?
That Daniel might not be your son?
다니엘이 당신의 아들이 아닐 수도 있다고요?
That I like you
내가 당신을 좋아한다는 것
is this something I deserve to be punished for?
이게 내가 벌을 받아야 할 일인가요?
Why did you do it?
왜 그랬나요?
You promised
약속했어요
don't say anything.
아무 말도 하지 마세요.
I know I was wrong,
내가 틀렸다는 걸 알아요
but only
하지만
I want him to cling to me.
그가 나에게 달라붙기를 바랍니다.